# Karim Abdelhalim

## Web & Mobile application react developer

#### **SUMMARY**

I am a passionate self-taught front-end developer. I love coding creative UIs and bringing designs to life with clean, efficient code. My expertise includes building responsive and user-friendly websites and applications, constantly learning and adapting to new technologies and trends to deliver the best digital experiences.

## **PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE**

## Front-end Developer at MedC

OCT 2023 - 2024

Collaborated with a skilled team to deliver a medical educational app, focusing on enhancing the user interface and experience.

• Development of Mobile application UI

• Development of website UI

• Links: website mobile app

Front-end Developer at Ringfill

DEC 2023 - 2024

Contributed to both frontend and backend development for various tasks such as:

• Development of Mobile application UI

• Enhancements on website

• Links: website mobile app

## **COURSEES & TRAININGS**

#### **DEPI** | React Development

April 2024 - OCT2024

## Ministry of communications Information, Egypt

- Cloud computing | web development (HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript)
- Front-end development (React.js, Tailwind CSS)
- Back-end development (node.js, Express.js, MongoDB)
- Soft Skills
- Business English

## Front-end Development

2023

# Almenor Platform

- Web development using HTML5 & CSS3
- Mastering CSS flex, CSS Grid & CSS Animation
- JavaScript for expert levels
- Git & GitHub

# **PROJECTS**

#### Babel library

- Description: A library app that offers a diverse collection of books, each with comprehensive information. It includes features such as a search bar, the ability to add books to your favorites, a reading progress tracker, and a dedicated screen for adding your favorite quotes.
- Technologies: Next.js, tailwind CSS, Shadon UI, React Native (expo), firebase, Figma
- Links: GitHub

# UnityCare hospital

- Description: This platform was developed to provide a comprehensive solution for healthcare services. It allows patients to easily book appointments, access information about doctors and specialties, and stay informed with the latest medical news.
- Technologies: Next.js, TypeScript, tailwind CSS, Shadcn UI, node.js, MongoDB

- Web Page

Links: - GitHub

## **CONTACTS**

**Phone**: (+20) 102 309 6263 **Address**: Egypt, Cairo

Email: Karimoda66@gmail.com

## **LINKS**

- LinkedIn
- GitHub
- Portfolio

## **EDUCATION**

ASU Mechanical engineering (Mechatronic department)

#### TECHNICAL SKILLS

# **Programing Languages**

- HTML
- Type Script
- CSS
- Python
- Java Scripts
- C++

#### Front-end

- React.js
- Next.js
- Shadcn UI
- React Native

## Back-end

- Node.js
- Express.js
- MongoDB
- Prisma

## **Version Control**

• Git

GitHub

### Design/Prototyping

• Figma

# **LANGUAGES**

Arabic (Native)

**English**